Register of the Allen Drury papers 65007.4088171
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence File, 1890-1994.
  - Owen, Carol, 1959 (Folder 19: 26)
  - Palm Beach Round Table, 1968-1985 (Folder 19: 27)
  - Palo Alto Times, 1948 (Folder 19: 28)
  - Panuch, J. Anthony, undated (Folder 19: 29)
  - Paramount Pictures Corporation, 1965 (Folder 19: 30)
  - Peng, C. Y., 1981 (Folder 19: 31)
  - Peninsula Newspapers Incorporated, 1954 (Folder 19: 32)
  - Peninsula Times Tribune, 1985 (Folder 19: 33)
  - Percy, Charles, 1973-1981 (Folder 19: 34)
  - Peterson, Ellen, 1978 (Folder 19: 35)
  - Phillips, Acting Assistant Secretary of State, 1969 (Folder 19: 36)
  - Piccone, D. N., 1969 (Folder 19: 37)
  - Players, 1968 (Folder 19: 38)
  - Pocket Books, Incorporated, 1960-1966 (Folder 19: 39)
  - Popular Library, Incorporated, 1969 (Folder 19: 40)
  - Powers, Ormund, 1972 (Folder 19: 41)
  - Prentice-Hall, Incorporated, 1969 (Folder 19: 42)
  - Prince of Spain, 1972 (Folder 19: 43)
  - Princeton University, Class of 1939, 1969 (Folder 19: 44)
  - Proxmire William, 1959 (Folder 19: 45)
  - Pulitzer, Joseph, Jr., 1966 (Folder 19: 46)
  - Rand McNally and Company, 1967 (Folder 19: 47)
  - Random House, Incorporated, 1969-1987 (Folder 19: 48)
  - Ray, Mrs. R. F., 1970 (Folder 19: 49)
  - Reade, Walter, 1969 (Folder 19: 50)
  - Reader's Digest, 1959-1977 (Folder 19: 51)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1966-1992 (Folder 19: 52)
  - Renault, Mary, 1976-1979 (Folder 19: 53)
  - Republic of China, 1981 (Folder 19: 54)
  - Republican National Committee, 1963-1964 (Folder 19: 55)
  - Republican State Central Committee, 1946-1947 (Folder 19: 56)
  - Rhoodie, E. M., 1971 (Folder 19: 57)
  - Ribicoff, Abraham, 1963-1972 (Folder 19: 58)
  - Riedel, Richard L., 1966-1969 (Folder 19: 59)
  - Robertson, Hugh W., 1959 (Folder 19: 60)
  - Rogers, Paul G., 1973 (Folder 19: 61)
  - Rollins College (Winter Park, Florida)
    - General, 1962-1974 (Folder 19: 62)
    - Annual Writer's Conference, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Roman, Paul, 1985 (Folder 20: 2)
  - Rovere, Richard, undated (Folder 20: 3)
  - Rudolph, Fred, 1972 (Folder 20: 4)
  - Rupert, A. E., 1970 (Folder 20: 5)
  - Rusk, Howard A., 1959 (Folder 20: 6)
  - Russell, Dick, 1963 (Folder 20: 7)
  - Ryan, Edward F., 1960 (Folder 20: 8)
  - Safire, William, 1990 (Folder 20: 9)
  - Salisbury, Harrison, 1971 (Folder 20: 10)
  - San Jose Mercury News, 1985 (Folder 20: 11)
  - Satterlee, Warfield and Steffus, 1965-1966 (Folder 20: 12)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1966 (Folder 20: 13)
  - Saturday Review, 1963 (Folder 20: 14)
  - Save the Children Federation, 1953 (Folder 20: 15)
  - Scheer, Julian, 1971 (Folder 20: 16)
  - Scheibla, Shirley, 1968 (Folder 20: 17)
  - Schmerler, Edward A., 1973 (Folder 20: 18)
  - Schulz, Charles M., 1970 (Folder 20: 19)
  - Schwarzkopf, Chet, 1970 (Folder 20: 20)
  - Scotland. Ministry of State, 1973 (Folder 20: 21)
  - Scott, Hugh, 1973 (Folder 20: 22)
  - Scott, Paul J., 1968-1969 (Folder 20: 23)
  - Seaton, Ed B., 1967 (Folder 20: 24)
  - Seidenbaum, Art, 1984 (Folder 20: 25)
  - Sephton, Nancy, 1968 (Folder 20: 26)
  - Sheffield, Marjorie, 1968-1971 (Folder 20: 27)
  - Sheinman, Mort, 1971 (Folder 20: 28)
  - Sias, Erwin, 1960 (Folder 20: 29)
  - Simon and Schuster, Incorporated, 1965-1987 (Folder 20: 30)
  - Simpson, Alan K., 1991-1993 (Folder 20: 31)
  - Simpson, Milward, 1963 (Folder 20: 32)
  - Singh, Karan, 1967 (Folder 20: 33)
  - Skolkin, Jesse, 1965 (Folder 20: 34)
  - Smathers, George A., 1961 (Folder 20: 35)
  - Smith, Margaret Chase, 1963 (Folder 20: 36)
  - Smith, Rose, 1973 (Folder 20: 37)
  - Snell, William N., 1960 (Folder 20: 38)
  - Solters and Sabinson, Incorporated, 1967-1968 (Folder 20: 39)
  - Spicer, Evelyn, 1967 (Folder 20: 40)
  - Staar, Richard, 1982 (Folder 20: 41)
  - Stanford University
    - General, 1959-1990 (Folder 20: 42)
    - Alumni Association, 1971-1994 (Folder 20: 43)
  - Steele, May, 1959 (Folder 20: 44)
  - Stevenson, Adlai, 1952 (Folder 20: 45)
  - Stevenson, William E., 1971 (Folder 20: 46)
  - Stewart, Potter, 1967-1968 (Folder 20: 47)
  - St. Johns, Adela Rogers, undated (Folder 20: 48)
  - St. Martin's Press, 1987-1988 (Folder 20: 49)
  - Stone, Helen, 1960 (Folder 20: 50)
  - Stone, Irving, 1979 (Folder 20: 51)
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 1969 (Folder 20: 52)
  - Strout, Dick, 1973 (Folder 20: 53)
  - Stuart, Mrs. Charles, 1971 (Folder 20: 54)
  - Stuart, Graham H., 1976 (Folder 20: 55)
  - Suzman, Helen, 1968-1969 (Folder 20: 56)
  - Swerling, Anthony, 1972 (Folder 20: 57)
  - Symington, Stuart, 1963 (Folder 20: 58)
  - Taft, Robert A., 1949 (Folder 20: 59)
  - Tahse, Martin, 1961-1962 (Folder 20: 60)
  - Talese, Gay, 1966 (Folder 20: 61)
  - Talmadge, Herman, 1963 (Folder 20: 62)
  - Tanner, Ann, 1973 (Folder 20: 63)
  - Tanzer, Lester, 1991 (Folder 20: 64)
  - Tarling, Ruth, 1973 (Folder 20: 65)
  - Thurmond, Strom, 1963 (Folder 20: 66)
  - Tidmarsh, George F., 1969 (Folder 20: 67)
  - Time, 1940-1993 (Folder 20: 68)
  - Tone, Pascal Franchot, 1972-1973 (Folder 20: 69)
  - Tower, John G., 1973 (Folder 20: 70)
  - Travel and Leisure, 1984 (Folder 20: 71)
  - Trident Press, 1966-1967 (Folder 20: 72)
  - Trohan, Walter, 1969-1971 (Folder 20: 73)
  - Truman, Harry S., 1959-1962 (Folder 20: 74)
  - Trussell, Tait, 1972 (Folder 20: 75)
  - Tucker, Ray, 1942 (Folder 20: 76)
  - Twentieth Century Fox Film Corporation, 1971-1981 (Folder 20: 77)
  - United States. Army War College, 1963 (Folder 20: 78)
  - United States. National Aeronautics and Space Agency, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - United States. National Endowment for the Arts, 1984-1989 (Folder 21: 2)
  - United States Information Agency, 1973-1983 (Folder 21: 3)
  - Universal Press Syndicate, 1985 (Folder 21: 4)
  - University Club (Orlando, Florida), 1968-1970 (Folder 21: 5)
  - University of Colorado (Boulder), 1972 (Folder 21: 6)
  - University of Notre Dame, Center for Continuing Studies, 1984 (Folder 21: 7)
  - Upton, J. Duane, undated (Folder 21: 8)
  - Uris, Leo, 1971 (Folder 21: 9)
  - Villacieros, Antonio, 1971 (Folder 21: 10)
  - Von Damm, Helene, 1982 (Folder 21: 11)
  - Wallace, De Witt, undated (Folder 21: 12)
  - Ward, Joan, undated (Folder 21: 13)
  - Washington Evening Star, 1971 (Folder 21: 14)
  - Washingtonian, 1989-1991 (Folder 21: 15)
  - Webster, Felice, 1969 (Folder 21: 16)
  - Webster, Martin H., 1963-1986 (Folder 21: 17)
  - Webster and Creamer Law Offices
    - 1969-1970 (Folder 21: 18)
    - 1970-1973 (Folder 21: 19)
  - Wertenbaker, Lael, 1974 (Folder 21: 20)
  - Western Review, 1964 (Folder 21: 21)
  - Wheeler, Burton K., 1963 (Folder 21: 22)
  - White, Carl J., 1969-1972 (Folder 21: 23)
  - White, Margita, 1970-1971 (Folder 21: 24)
  - White, Theodore H., 1973 (Folder 21: 25)
  - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, 1941 (Folder 21: 26)
  - Wilcox, Francis O., 1961 (Folder 21: 27)
  - William Morris Agency, 1946-1983 (Folder 21: 28)
  - William Morrow and Company, 1974-1992 (Folder 21: 29)
  - Williams, Andy, 1977 (Folder 21: 30)
  - Willkie, Wendell, 1941-1943 (Folder 21: 31)
  - Wilson, Mary, 1959 (Folder 21: 32)
  - Wilson, Pete, 1988-1989 (Folder 21: 33)
  - Wing, Willis K., 1958-1966 (Folder 21: 34)
  - Winslow, Ward, 1959 (Folder 21: 35)
  - Wisehart, M. K., 1959 (Folder 21: 36)
  - Wiseman, John I., 1959 (Folder 21: 37)
  - Wolfe, Noran, 1968 (Folder 21: 38)
  - World Book Year Book (Chicago), 1964-1967 (Folder 21: 39)
  - Wouk, Herman, 1965-1992 (Folder 21: 40)
  - Wouk, Jonathan, 1968 (Folder 21: 41)
  - WPEN Broadcasting Company, 1951 (Folder 21: 42)
  - Writers Digest, 1966-1967 (Folder 21: 43)
  - Writers Guild of America, 1977 (Folder 21: 44)
  - Yarborough, Ralph W., 1964 (Folder 21: 45)
  - Young, Loretta, 1977 (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - Young, Milton, 1963-1973 (Folder 22: 2)
  - Young Americans for Freedom, 1970 (Folder 22: 3)
  - Younger, J. Arthur, 1964 (Folder 22: 4)
  - Ziegler, Ronald, 1971 (Folder 22: 5)
  - Zumwalt, E. R., 1973 (Folder 22: 6)
- Speeches and Writings, 1932-1995.
  Handwritten, typewritten, and printed copies of speeches and writings, with related notes and research materials, arranged chronologically
  - General
    - General. Miscellaneous drafts and notes
      - 1960-1986 (Folder 22: 7)
      - 1987 (Folder 22: 8)
      - 1988-1989 (Folder 22: 9)
    - List of "Westerner in Washington" columns in the Palo Alto Times, 1946-1954. (Folder 22: 10)
      Typescripts
    - Untitled drafts and notes, undated (Folder 22: 11)
    - Untitled essays relating to the Democratic Party, undated (Folder 22: 12)
  - "All Things Considered,", undated. (Folder 22: 13)
    Typescript
  - "Bandstand,", undated. (Folder 22: 14)
  - "Based on the Novel,", undated. (Folder 22: 15)
  - "Basic Guidelines for Those Who Want to Write,", undated. (Folder 22: 16)
  - "By the Sign of the Grapevine,", undated. (Folder 22: 17)
  - "Can the UN Survive Its Own Hatreds?", undated. (Folder 22: 18)
  - "The Capital Movers,", undated. (Folder 22: 19)
  - "The Chosen,", undated. (Folder 22: 20)
  - "The Dawning Soul: Lichfield Years,", undated. (Folder 22: 21)
  - "Faces of a God against the Gods and Return to Thebes,", undated. (Folder 22: 22)
    Holograph
  - "The Flapper's Dirge,", undated. (Folder 22: 23)
  - "Ghosts in the Government," Esquire, undated. (Folder 22: 24)
  - "The Governors at Gatlinburg,", undated. (Folder 22: 25)
  - "Harry Byrd: Last of the Great Virginians,", undated. (Folder 22: 26)
  - "The Image of America," CBS News broadcast, with Edward Murrow as narrator, undated. (Folder 22: 27)
  - "The Ladies of Politics,", undated. (Folder 22: 28)
  - "The Lesson,", undated. (Folder 22: 29)
  - Letter to the editor, Magazine of Books, undated. (Folder 22: 30)
    Clipping
  - "Mr. Chairman,", undated. (Folder 22: 31)
  - "Mr. Nixon Goes to Washington,", undated. (Folder 22: 32)
  - "Other Hands,", undated. (Folder 22: 33)
  - "Second Paper,", undated. (Box-folder 23: 1)
  - "Senate Foreign Relations,", undated. (Folder 23: 2)
  - "Senator Humphrey,", undated. (Folder 23: 3)
  - "The Sounds of Spring,", undated. (Folder 23: 4)
  - "Taxation, No Tyranny,", undated. (Folder 23: 5)
  - "Times Talk,", undated. (Folder 23: 6)
  - Untitled note on Adolf Hitler, undated. (Folder 23: 7)
  - "The Uses of Innocence,", undated. (Folder 23: 8)
  - "Washington Story,", undated. (Folder 23: 9)
  - "The Haunted Ghost,", 1932. (Folder 23: 10)
  - "Where Go the Boats?", 1932. (Folder 23: 11)
  - "After the Fall of Arthur,", 1933. (Folder 23: 12)
  - "Creeping Jungle,", 1933. (Folder 23: 13)
  - "The Diaries,", 1933. (Folder 23: 14)
  - "The Fire,", 1933. (Folder 23: 15)
  - "Rain over the Chinese Hotel,", 1933. (Folder 23: 16)
  - "Somewhere,", 1933. (Folder 23: 17)
  - "The Square,", 1933 May. (Folder 23: 18)
  - "African Nights,", 1934. (Folder 23: 19)
  - "Cameos,", 1934. (Folder 23: 20)
  - "Cavalcade,", 1934. (Folder 23: 21)
  - "The Dance of Clan Deorg,", 1934. (Folder 23: 22)
  - "The Discovery of Plosh,", 1934. (Folder 23: 23)
  - "The Dream,", 1934. (Folder 23: 24)
  - "First Gold Discovered January 1848,", 1934. (Folder 23: 25)
  - "God Took a Sod,", 1934. (Folder 23: 26)
  - "Hands,", 1934. (Folder 23: 27)
  - "Jape,", 1934. (Folder 23: 28)
  - "Lights in Ravenscote,", 1934. (Folder 23: 29)
  - "Only the Peacocks, across the Water,", 1934. (Folder 23: 30)
  - "Other Hands,", 1934. (Folder 23: 31)
  - "The Queen is Dead,", 1934. (Folder 23: 32)
  - "Question on Olympus,", 1934. (Folder 23: 33)
  - "Reserved: 1934," (Folder 23: 34)
  - "Three Ring Impressions,", 1934. (Folder 23: 35)
  - "Trivia,", 1934 January. (Folder 23: 36)
  - "Cicero and Something about Reconstruction,", 1934 February. (Folder 23: 37)
  - "Herr Vanterhoff,", 1934 March. (Folder 23: 38)
  - "Nero: Poetic Soul,", 1934 March. (Folder 23: 39)
  - "Six People,", 1934 May. (Folder 23: 40)
  - "The Private Lives of the Emperors,", 1934 June 12. (Folder 23: 41)
  - "Dusk,", 1934 October. (Folder 23: 42)
  - "Camel and Gold to Samarkand,", 1935. (Folder 23: 43)
  - "Discobolus,", 1935. (Folder 23: 44)
  - "Hans Joseph Waited,", 1935. (Folder 23: 45)
  - "Music across a Lake in the Welsh Mountains,", 1935. (Folder 23: 46)
  - "The Pilot,", 1935. (Folder 23: 47)
  - "Caesar Borgia - A Dramalogue," Cargo, Stanford University, Volume VI, no. 2, 1936. (Folder 23: 48)
  - "Rain, Rain, Go Away,", 1936. (Folder 23: 49)
  - "Suspended Animation,", 1936 January 20. (Folder 23: 50)
  - "His Soul Goes Marching - A Play for John Brown,", 1936 October. (Folder 23: 51)
  - "Venus and Adonis,", 1936 October. (Folder 23: 52)
  - "The Big War of 1938,", 1936 November. (Folder 23: 53)
  - "On Your Dark Journeys," written for Jim Weter, 1937 June. (Folder 23: 54)
  - Articles for the Stanford Daily, 1938-1939. (Folder 23: 55)
  - "The Need for Skepticism,", 1938. (Folder 23: 56)
  - "I Have Been to College,", 1938 December. (Folder 23: 57)
    Typescript. Includes 1939 version
  - Untitled note relating to the moral dilemma of youth, 1939. (Folder 23: 58)
  - "Comes Soon the Glad Tomorrow," A Yearbook of Stanford Writing, Stanford University, 1939 May. (Folder 23: 59)
  - American history paper, Stanford University, 1939 July 14. (Folder 23: 60)
  - Interview, Portersville, California, 1939 October 10. (Folder 23: 61)
  - "Citizenship,", 1940. (Folder 23: 62)
  - Editorials in the Tulare Bee, 1940. (Box-folder 24: 1)
    Clippings
  - Articles published in the Tulare Bee, 1940 January-November. (Folder 24: 2)
    Printed copies
  - "For a Graduating Class," New Mexico Quarterly, 1940 May. (Folder 24: 3)
  - "Wendell Willkie in the West,", 1940 September 20. (Folder 24: 4)
  - "Where Do We Stand with Britain?", 1941. (Folder 24: 5)
  - Articles published in the Tulare Bee, 1941 January-February. (Folder 24: 6)
    Typescripts and printed copies
  - "National Sigma Delta Chi Award Editorial," Tulare Bee, 1941 March 20. (Folder 24: 7)
  - Letters to the editor, Bakersfield Californian, 1941 May - 1942 June. (Folder 24: 8)
  - Statement of acceptance, Sigma Delta Chi Distinguished Service Award for Editorial Writing, 1941 November 15. (Folder 24: 9)
  - Radio program for the Bakersfield City Defense Council, 1942 April 30. (Folder 24: 10)
  - Editorials in the Tulare Bee, 1943. (Folder 24: 11)
  - "The Moral Basis for Peace,", 1943 January. (Folder 24: 12)
  - Address to the members of the Lions Club, 1946 (Folder 24: 13)
  - "A Westerner in Washington,", 1948 June. (Folder 24: 14)
  - "The Fundamental Issue," Congressional Record, 1948 June 7. (Folder 24: 15)
  - "Mr. Chairman, etc.," speech, Texas, 1948 December. (Folder 24: 16)
  - Samples, entered in competition for the 1949 Sigma Delta Chi Award for Magazine Writing (Folder 24: 17)
  - "How Mr. Truman Does It: A Lesson for Republicans,", 1950 January. (Folder 24: 18)
  - Speech, McDonogh School for Boys, McDonogh, Maryland, 1952 May. (Folder 24: 19)
  - "How the Wise Old Politicians Kept the Democrats from Splitting," Pathfinder, 1952 August 6. (Folder 24: 20)
  - "The Change," Pathfinder, 1952 December 3. (Folder 24: 21)
  - Speech, CBS audition, 1953 January. (Folder 24: 22)
  - Untitled article for the Sunday Star, 1953 February 15. (Folder 24: 23)
  - "Shape of Things to Come," Evening Star, 1953 May 8. (Folder 24: 24)
  - "Six Months of Eisenhower," Sunday Star, 1953 July 19. (Folder 24: 25)
  - "Velde Inquiry Find Oxnam is Not Communist," Evening Star, 1953 July 22. (Folder 24: 26)
  - "A New Republican Party Travels on the Eisenhower Bandwagon," Pathfinder, 1953 July 23. (Folder 24: 27)
  - "Ohioan Thwarted Four Times in Presidential Nomination Bids," Evening Star, 1953 July 31. (Folder 24: 28)
  - "How Fast Can Changes Be Made?" Pathfinder, 1953 November 19. (Folder 24: 29)
  - "McCarthy Elbows into Spotlight," Minneapolis Star, 1953 November 24. (Folder 24: 30)
  - "Washington and War: The Search for a Policy,", 1955. (Folder 24: 31)
  - "The Enigma of Gettysburg," The Reporter, 1955 December 29. (Folder 24: 32)
  - Speech, Presbyterian Men's Council, Catonsville, Maryland, 1957 October 4. (Box-folder 25: 1)
  - Speech, McDonogh School for Boys, McDonogh, Maryland, 1958 February 28. (Folder 25: 2)
  - Advise and Consent (1959)
    - Outline, 1950. (Folder 25: 3)
    - Notes, 1957-1961 (Folder 25: 4)
    - Preface, not included in final publication, undated. (Folder 25: 5)
    - Chapter I, 1950. (Folder 25: 6)
    - Chapter II, undated. (Folder 25: 7)
    - Cables, 1960 (Folder 25: 8)
    - "A and C on the Road,", 1960 October 16. (Folder 25: 9)
    - Clippings, 1959-1961 (Folder 25: 10)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1959-1961 (Folder 25: 11)
      - Johnson, Reverdy, 1960 (Folder 25: 12)
      - Preminger, Otto, 1961 (Folder 25: 13)
    - Interview with Voice of America, 1959 August 28. (Folder 25: 14)
    - Motion picture, 1959-1961 (Folder 25: 15)
    - Plays
      - Script of Broadway play, undated. (Folder 25: 16)
      - Mandel, Loring, play based on Advise and Consent, 1960. (Folder 25: 17)
        Programs and correspondence
    - Memorandum, 1961 (Folder 25: 18)
    - Reviews
      - General
        - 1959 (Folder 25: 19)
        - 1959-1960 (Box-folder 26: 1)
      - Drummond, Roscoe, Book of the Month Club, 1959 midsummer (Folder 26: 2)
      - George, Damiel, "Warfare in Washington," The Bookman, 1960 January/February (Folder 26: 3)
    - Screenplay, 1961. (Folder 26: 4)
    - Unidentified school project based on Advise and Consent, undated. (Folder 26: 5)
  - "Allen Drury Consents and Advises," The Blue and Gray, No. 2, 1959. (Folder 26: 6)
  - "The Rose Colored Country,", 1959. (Folder 26: 7)
  - Speech, Washington Booksellers, 1959 May 13. (Folder 26: 8)
  - Speech, National Press Club, 1959 August 8. (Folder 26: 9)
  - Speech, Citizenship Clearing House, Hershey, Pennsylvania, 1959 September 7. (Folder 26: 10)
  - Speech, Pennsylvania State Library Association, York, Pennsylvania, 1959 October 2. (Folder 26: 11)
  - "Senator Mansfield,", 1960. (Folder 26: 12)
  - "Something," Fantasy and Science Fiction, 1960. (Folder 26: 13)
  - "A Need for Affirmation," speech, New York Herald Tribune Book and Author Club, 1960 January 18. (Folder 26: 14)
  - Speech, Sulgrave Club, 1960 February 17. (Folder 26: 15)
  - "Odds-on Favorite," American Weekly, 1960 March 20. (Folder 26: 16)
  - Speech, Women's National Press Club, 1960 April 7. (Folder 26: 17)
  - "The Greatest Political Shows on Earth," Reader's Digest, 1960 July. (Folder 26: 18)
  - Breadloaf evening lecture, 1960 August. (Folder 26: 19)
  - "How to Win an Election," Reader's Digest, 1960 November. (Folder 26: 20)
  - "You - United States Senator,", 1961. (Folder 26: 21)
  - Speech in connection with receiving honorary degree of Doctor of Letters, Rollins College, Winter Park, Florida, 1961 February 26. (Folder 26: 22)
  - Speech, Rotary Club, Porterville, California, 1961 March 19. (Folder 26: 23)
  - "Education for Politics," Rollins College Bulletin, 1961 April. (Folder 26: 24)
  - Speech, White House Photographers Magazine, annual banquet of the president, 1961 May 19. (Folder 26: 25)
  - Speech, Aspen Institute, 1961 August 1. (Folder 26: 26)
  - A Shade of Difference (1962)
    - Notes, 1959-1960 (Folder 26: 27)
    - Chapters I-IV, undated. (Folder 26: 28)
    - Final manuscript, 1962. (Box-folder 27: 1-7)
    - Final manuscript, 1962. (Box-folder 28: 1)
    - Galley proofs, 1962 (Folder 28: 2-3)
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Folder 28: 4)
    - Promotional leaflet/order form, undated (Folder 28: 5)
    - Reviews, 1962-1963 (Folder 28: 6)
  - "Congressional Committees,", 1962 December. (Folder 28: 7)
  - "Guest Column for Holmes Alexander,", 1962 December. (Folder 28: 8)
  - "We-Know-Best School Hides, Distorts Facts on Foreign Policy," St. Louis Globe-Democrat, 1962 December 1. (Folder 28: 9)
  - "Can the UN Survive Its Own Hatreds?", 1962 December 11. (Folder 28: 10)
  - "The American Responsibility,", 1963. (Folder 28: 11)
  - A Senate Journal (1963) (Box 29)
    - First version titled "What the Hall, They're Human,", 1962. (Folder 29: 1-6)
    - First version titled "What the Hall, They're Human,", 1962. (Box-folder 30: 1-3)
    - Second version, undated. (Folder 30: 4-6)
    - Second version, undated. (Box-folder 31: 1-6)
    - Final version, undated. (Box-folder 32: 1-6)
    - Final version, undated. (Box-folder 33: 1-6)
    - Final version, undated. (Box-folder 34: 1-4)
    - Galley proofs, 1963 (Folder 34: 5-6)
    - Galley proofs, 1963 (Box-folder 35: 1-6)
    - Galley proofs, 1963 (Box-folder 36: 1-6)
    - Galley proofs, 1963 (Box-folder 37: 1-3)
    - Correspondence with McGraw-Hill Book Company (Edward Kuhn), regarding corrections in the manuscript, 1963 (Folder 37: 4)
    - Reviews
      - General, 1963 (Folder 37: 5)
      - Themal, Henry, 1963 (Folder 37: 6)
  - "Comments for Granik Program,", 1963 January. (Folder 37: 7)
  - Speech, Philadelphia Book and Author Club, 1963 January 23. (Folder 37: 8)
  - "When You Go before a Congressional Committee," Think, 1963 March. (Folder 37: 9)
  - "The Roosevelt Record,", 1963 April 16. (Folder 37: 10)
  - Debate on critics, 1963 April 19. (Folder 37: 11)
  - United Nations speech, 1963 May 21. (Folder 37: 12)
  - "The Genesis of the Third World War,", 1963 June. (Box-folder 38: 1-3)
  - Three Kids in a Cart (1965)
    - Typescript, undated
      - First version (Folder 38: 4-6)
      - Final version (Box-folder 39: 1-2)
    - Galley proofs, undated (Folder 39: 3)
    - Reviews
      - General, 1965-1966 (Folder 39: 4)
      - Baird, Dorwin and Verna, 1965 (Folder 39: 5)
  - "A Challenge to America - The View from Washington," address to the Brigham Young University student body, 1965 October 21. (Folder 39: 6)
  - Capable of Honor (1966)
    - Typescript, undated (Folder 39: 7)
    - Typescript, undated (Box-folder 40: 1-6)
    - Typescript, undated (Box-folder 41: 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Folder 41: 2)
    - Reviews
      - General, 1966-1967 (Folder 41: 3-4)
      - Gordon, Michael, undated (Folder 41: 5)
      - K.H.B.V., 1966 (Folder 41: 6)
  - That Summer (1966)
    - Typescript, undated (Folder 41: 7-8)
    - Correspondence, 1965 (Folder 41: 9)
    - Reviews, 1966 (Folder 41: 10)
  - Letter to the editor, Writer's Digest, 1966 February. (Folder 41: 11)
  - A Very Strange Society (1967) (Box 42)
    - Typescript, undated (Folder 42: 1-7)
    - Typescript, undated (Box-folder 43: 1-7)
    - Galley proofs, undated (Box-folder 44: 1)
    - Correspondence, 1968 (Folder 44: 2)
    - Reviews, 1967-1968 (Folder 44: 3-4)
  - Preserve and Protect (1968)
    - Typescript, undated (Folder 44: 5-6)
    - Typescript, undated (Box-folder 45: 1)
    - Typescript with editors' corrections, undated (Folder 45: 2-6)
    - Galley proofs, undated (Box-folder 46: 1)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1967-1968 (Folder 46: 2)
      - Harold Matson Company, 1968 (Folder 46: 3)
    - Reviews, 1968-1969 (Folder 46: 4-5)
    - Statement by Allen Drury, 1968 May 18 (Folder 46: 6)
  - "Dot's Nize," Eleventh annual San Francisco International Film Festival, 1968 October 20-29. (Folder 46: 7)
  - "The Peaceful Passage of Power,", 1968 November. (Folder 46: 8)
  - Interview with Susan Ludel for Ayn Rand's The Objectivist, 1968 December. (Folder 46: 9)
  - "How the Power of the Presidency is Passed On," Family Weekly, 1969 January 19. (Folder 46: 10)
  - "The Defeatless Man: MR. Nixon Goes to Washington," Reader's Digest, 1969 February. (Folder 46: 11)
    Typescript. Includes letter from Rose Mary Woods, 1969 February 12
  - "Bandstand,", 1969 March. (Folder 46: 12)
  - Speech, Palm Beach Round Table, 1970 January 12. (Folder 46: 13)
  - Review of William Gill, The Ordeal of Otto Otepka, 1970 August 10. (Folder 46: 14)
  - Courage and Hesitation (1971) (Box 47)
    - Interviews and notes, 1970-1971 (Folder 47: 1-2)
    - Typescript, undated (Folder 47: 3-5)
    - Press releases, 1971-1972 (Folder 47: 6)